{
    "quiz": {
        "Java": {
            "q1": {
                "question": "Java is a high-level language.",
                "options": [
                    "True",
                    "False"
                ],
                "answer": "True",
                "Explanation": "Java is a high-level language because it is more easily understood by humans, Low=-level languages are always static."
            },
            "q2": {
                "question": "What kind of language is java?",
                "options": [
                    "Functional Language",
                    "Procedural Language",
                    "Object-Oriented Language",
                    "Structured Language"
                ],
                "answer": "Object-Oriented Language",
                "Explanation": "Java is an Object-Oriented Language."

            },
            "q3": {
                "question": "What is the result of 24 % 5? ",
                "options": [
                    "4",
                    "5",
                    "4.8",
                    "24"
                ],
                "answer": "4",
                "Explanation": "% finds the remainder of an expression, the remainder of 24/5 being 4"
            },
            "q4": {
                "question": "What is the default value of an integer?",
                "options": [
                    "Null",
                    "0",
                    "Not Assigned",
                    "1"
                ],
                "answer": "0",
                "Explanation": "When an integer is called and not defined, the default value is 0"
            },
            "q5": {
                "question": "What is the default value of an object?",
                "options": [
                    "Null",
                    "0",
                    "Not Assigned",
                    "1"
                ],
                "answer": "Not Assigned",
                "Explanation": "When an object is not defined, the default value is Not Assigned"
            },
            "q6": {
                "question": "Is it possible to have multiple classes in the same java file?",
                "options": [
                    "Yes",
                    "No"
                ],
                "answer": "Yes",
                "Explanation": "It is possible to have multiple classes in the same java file."
            },
            "q7": {
                "question": "What does multiple inheritance mean?",
                "options": [
                    "Multiple classes inheriting from more super classes",
                    "Multiple classes inheriting from one super class",
                    "One class inheriting from multiple super classes",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "One class inheriting from multiple super classes",
                "Explanation": "Multiple inheritance in java allows for one class to inherit from multiple super classes."
            },
            "q8": {
                "question": "What is the process that involves recognizing and focusing on the important characteristics of a situation or object is known as",
                "options": [
                    "Encapsulation",
                    "Polymorphism",
                    "Abstraction",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "Abstraction",
                "Explanation": "Abstraction is the process that involves recognizing and focusing on the important characteristics of a situation or object."
            },
            "q9": {
                "question": "Is it possible to change the length of an array after it is made?",
                "options": [
                    "Yes",
                    "No"
                ],
                "answer": "No",
                "Explanation": "Arrays are static length."
            },
            "q10": {
                "question": "Is it possible to change the length of an arraylist after it is made?",
                "options": [
                    "Yes",
                    "No"
                ],
                "answer": "Yes",
                "Explanation": "Arraylists are not static in length."
            },
            "q11": {
                "question": "What is a package a collection of?",
                "options": [
                    "Classes",
                    "Methods",
                    "Classes and Interfaces",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "Classes and Interfaces",
                "Explanation": "Packages are collections of classes and interfaces."
            },
            "q12": {
                "question": "Which of the following are keywords?",
                "options": [
                    "abstract",
                    "switch",
                    "throw",
                    "void",
                    "All of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "All of the above",
                "Explanation": "All of the options are keywords, the list of all of them can be found here: https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/nutsandbolts/_keywords.html"
            },
            "q13": {
                "question": "Which of the following are Java IDEs?",
                "options": [
                    "Netbeans",
                    "Eclipse",
                    "IntelliJ IDEA",
                    "All of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "All of the above",
                "Explanation": "All of the above are Java IDEs."
            },
            "q14": {
                "question": "What of the following are methods to create a GUI in java?",
                "options": [
                    "Swing",
                    "JavaFX",
                    "Java IO",
                    "First and Second Options"
                ],
                "answer": "First and Second Options",
                "Explanation": "Java Swing and JavaFX can be used to create a GUI in java"
            },
            "q15": {
                "question": "What is the output of the following code? \nint count;\nfor (int i=0; i==20; i++)\ncount++;\nSystem.out.println(count);",
                "options": [
                    "5",
                    "20",
                    "Count",
                    "None of the Above"
                ],
                "answer": "20",
                "Explanation": "The for loop counts up and adds adds one to count until it hits 20."
            },
            "q16": {
                "question": "What is the output of the following code? \nArrayList<String> fruits = new ArrayList<String>();\nfruits.add(\"Apple\");\nfruits.add(\"Pear\");\nfruits.add(\"Grape\");\nSystem.out.println(fruits.get(1));",
                "options": [
                    "Apple",
                    "Pear",
                    "Grape",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "Pear",
                "Explanation": "The 1st element of the array is pear since the 0th element is whatever is added first."
            },
            "q17": {
                "question": "What is the quantity of the following arraylist?\nArrayList list = new ArrayList();",
                "options": [
                    "0",
                    "10",
                    "100",
                    "Null"
                ],
                "answer": "10",
                "Explanation": "The default quantity of an ArrayList is 10."
            },
            "q18": {
                "question": "What is the output of the following code? int num[] = {1,2,3,4,5};\nfor(int i=0;i< x; ++i)\nSystem.out.println(values[i]);  ",
                "options": [
                    "5",
                    "1",
                    "0",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "None of the above",
                "Explanation": "The variable x is not initalized, so the code will not execute and will result in an error. "
            },
            "q19": {
                "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nSystem.out.println(50/0)",
                "options": [
                    "Infinity",
                    "Zero",
                    "java.lang.ArithmeticException",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "java.lang.ArithmeticException",
                "Explanation": "Dividing an integer by 0 results in java.lang.ArithmeticException"
            },
            "q20": {
                "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nSystem.out.print(\"Hello\");\nSystem.out.println(\"World!\"",
                "options": [
                    "Hello\nWorld!",
                    "Hello World!",
                    "HelloWorld!",
                    "Hello\n World!"
                ],
                "answer": "HelloWorld!",
                "Explanation": "System.out.print() does not print a new line after printing."
            }
        }
    }
}